<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Second Drafts</title>
<link>https://github.com/apurvanakade/second-drafts/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://github.com/apurvanakade/second-drafts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 13:11:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Begin Again</title>
  <dc:creator>Apurva Nakade</dc:creator>
  <link>https://github.com/apurvanakade/second-drafts/posts/begin-again.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p>I opened this page with a clear idea of what I wanted to write. I’ve now spent the last half hour updating quarto, setting up a new git repository, fixing a git merge issue, figuring out how to render drafts… this was a mistake. When I have something to write, I need to get the words out as soon as possible without worrying about their final destination.</p>
<hr>
<p>One of the protagonist in <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10357575-1q84">1Q84</a>, Tengo, is a writer. He teaches math at cram schools to make a living but his real passion is writing. At some point in his life he has to decide between writing and math, and he decides to write. Tengo is my alter-ego from a different dimension. He chose writing just as I chose math. Thankfully math pays so I do not have to teach writing for a living.</p>
<p>I’ve always loved writing. I have had several blogs representing different phrases of my life, each reflective of what I was going through at the time but haven’t maintained one of late for various inane excuses.</p>
<p>I recently started reading <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/615570.The_Artist_s_Way">The Artist’s Way</a> and it inspired me to write again. I sometimes get stuck in arguments, trying to find reasons to justify doing or not doing something, analysis paralysis. Very simply though, I just enjoy putting thoughts into words, which is justification enough to write. I heard Neil Gaiman talk about how he likes to write with a fountain pen. Writing here is the equivalent of writing with a fountain pen for me - just watching words magically appear on the screen out of nowhere.</p>
<p>This journal is going to be a collection of my second drafts - nothing polished or well-thought but not stream-of-conscious either. As Sam Harris says, it’s never late to <a href="https://dynamic.wakingup.com/course/CO7C3B8B5">begin again</a>.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://github.com/apurvanakade/second-drafts/posts/begin-again.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 13:11:32 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
