<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Second Drafts</title>
<link>https://github.com/apurvanakade/second-drafts/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://github.com/apurvanakade/second-drafts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 13:11:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Begin Again</title>
  <dc:creator>Apurva Nakade</dc:creator>
  <link>https://github.com/apurvanakade/second-drafts/posts/begin-again.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p>I opened this page with a clear idea of what to write. I’ve now spent the last half an hour updating quarto, creating a new github repository, fixing a git merge issue on the old repository, figuring out how to render drafts… This was a mistake. When I have something to write, I need to get the words out as soon as possible without worrying about where they are going to go.</p>
<hr>
<p>One of the protagonist in <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10357575-1q84">1Q84</a>, Tengo, is a writer. He teaches math at cram schools to make a living but his real passion is writing. At some point in his life he as to decide between writing and math, and he decides to write.</p>
<p>Tengo is my alter-ego from a different dimension - funny that the book itself is about different dimensions. He chose writing where as I chose math. Thankfully math pays so I do not have to teach writing for a living.</p>
<p>I’ve always loved writing. I have had several blogs representing different phrases of my life, each reflective of what I was going through at the time. I haven’t blogged in the past few years.</p>
<ul>
<li>I wanted to focus more on math writing and my work.</li>
<li>Do people write any more? Isn’t this the age of videos?</li>
<li>Why write a blog at all that nobody reads?</li>
<li>… so many excuses.</li>
</ul>
<p>Recently I started reading <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/615570.The_Artist_s_Way">The Artist’s Way</a> and it inspired me to write again. I sometimes get stuck in logic and rationalizing and trying to find reasons to do something. But really, I just enjoy putting thoughts into words, and that is reason enough. I heard Neil Gaiman talk about how he likes to write with a fountain pen. And I do too, I find it magical to see words appear on paper. But, I write much slower on paper than I can think. And I move around a lot so I do not have the luxury of carrying ink cartridges with me. For me, writing here is the equivalent of writing with a fountain pen. Just watching words magically appear on the screen out of nowhere.</p>
<p>I’m calling this journal Second Drafts as that’s what it’s going to be. Nothing polished or well-thought but not stream-of-conscious either. I hope to write what comes to mind and then do one scan to clean it up. As Sam Harris says, it’s never late to begin again.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://github.com/apurvanakade/second-drafts/posts/begin-again.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 13:11:32 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
