<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>First Drafts</title>
<link>https://github.com/apurvanakade/first-drafts/</link>
<atom:link href="https://github.com/apurvanakade/first-drafts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.7.29</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 13:11:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Begin Again</title>
  <dc:creator>Apurva Nakade</dc:creator>
  <link>https://github.com/apurvanakade/first-drafts/posts/begin-again.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>I opened this page with a clear idea of what to write. I’ve now spent the last half an hour updating quarto, creating a new github repository, fixing a git merge issue on the old repository, figuring out how to render drafts… This was a mistake. When I have something to write, I need to get the words out as soon as possible without worrying about where are going to go.</p>
<hr>
<p>One of the protagonist in <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10357575-1q84">1Q84</a>, Tengo, is a writer. He teaches math at cram schools to make a living but his real passion is writing. At some point in his life he as to decide between writing and math, and he decides to write.</p>
<p>Tengo is my alter-ego from a different dimension - funny that the book itself is about different dimensions, as is always the case with Murakami’s novels. I don’t have a talent for writing but I’ve always loved writing. I have had several blogs in different parts of my life each quite reflective of the what I was going through at the time.</p>
<p>I haven’t blogged in the past few years. I can think of many excuses.</p>
<ul>
<li>I wanted to focus more on math writing and my work.</li>
<li>Do people write any more? Isn’t this the age of videos?</li>
<li>Why write a blog at all that nobody reads?</li>
</ul>
<p>But then recently I started reading <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/615570.The_Artist_s_Way">The Artist’s Way</a> and it inspired me to write again.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://github.com/apurvanakade/first-drafts/posts/begin-again.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 13:11:32 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
